all right welcome to our board meeting
and as soon as I went live
it'll join I keep forgetting you can add
yourself I'm just gonna give the intro
it's like we're ahead of the curve we've
been doing our remote board meeting he
from remote locations since we started
no harder for companies that aren't used
to doing it remotely
now take up we know remotely this is our
project of projects then a project or
meaning of how I think any of us have
done much with the Facebook group as far
as um figuring out how to get people to
these meetings how to get people we have
enough participation in the solution and
project raisins but how to get new faces
and so people know what's going on I
feel it's the same problems as usual
just the algorithm people being busy
with pandemics and other other such life
problems but so I just opened the agenda
and linked to this video but didn't
actually put anything on the agenda nor
did I watch two weeks ago was one to
refresh myself what we're talking about
this meeting trying to get people to
show up to it is it at all like is this
time set in stone for both of you
because the 11:00 a.m. Pen is it being
weird cuz it runs right after a pretty
important meeting for me that happens
weekly I'm pretty flexible okay okay
even if we just pushed it forward an
hour that would be awesome we can do
noon instead of alone yeah that should
work okay honestly if you onus wants to
come they'd also work better for us I'm
just like an hour later so instead of it
being ridiculously ridiculously early
it's only ridiculously early you know
maybe create a website introducing game
be as a new we're just gonna put this up
here so I don't even know that
Renaissance the website would have a
filtering system that allowed people to
find groups solving problems they are
most interested in yeah that'd be great
make that that's what I posted a video
add someone to make the scheduler and I
got a lot of other things out of it but
no one who's like yes I can make that
because right now all the introverts or
extroverts are inside what a great time
to communicate that video chat is the
way to connect with people because
introverts don't know that it's the
answer to that problem extroverts would
it's like when they're stuck inside
operating teams on have we heard of this
one before I don't think so
twist don't know we'll check it out oh
never heard of that either
I did however on the post where I posted
about the scheduler in game B
unfortunately Facebook I think you're
proposing from the project page is my
guess because if it's where we're live
so I don't know how you would post if
you weren't there but we cannot see who
you are but we'll see who you are after
yes any help is always always great
especially game be help from people who
are web developers bye posted for the
scheduler because it would be great if
someone could make maybe I just
overestimate how simple the scheduler is
that I'm like um someone who knows how
to do it could do it in a weekend or a
week and hey you're stuck at home anyway
why not why not do this so that society
can come together and work on solutions
or just talk about the game last night
or have a religious ceremony literally
anything that's via video chat will
people are social having to socially
distance their baby there will be some
people who because their home will have
nothing to do most everyone I know
though has remote work capabilities so
it's it's actually increasing the
workload on a few people but yeah maybe
someone has a job that isn't remote a
bowl that would have a little time yeah
and then I also I watched your video
Julie and I I thought made it might be
helpful to try to narrow down the
requirements of the
of the scheduling app so I took a crack
at writing those down if we want to it's
part of the agenda we can go over those
and just make sure that that's correct
and then the right priority order yeah
and Nick on my youtube-channel had made
a comment about a tool for what did he
say I'm gonna go look it up someone else
talk I'm gonna go look up what he said
online cuz he also gave this oh don't
don't talk what happens with my you guys
the talk I wanted me not to knock across
the video and maybe for that Facebook
user that we can't see their identity
web graphic designer the question comes
in do you have any back-end skills that
could because this system will need a
back in so fronting will help and it'd
be good to know whether you're
exclusively front yeah I was looking at
open-source projects to see what pieces
are there and there's a couple of you
eyes that are pre-built but actually
none of them had an easy way to make a
recurring appointment so I'm trying to
think whether we even like for v11 to
have its where you just say what days of
the week you're available you know
something really simple because
repeating calendar appointments can be
challenging to calculate I have me
someone that came from the game be post
at first I just wanted to read what I
have open which is take said take a
moment and draw a flow chart of the
minimum process on whimsical calm with
Jose I think they have a free option to
draw which is not how my mind works for
tech because I wouldn't know to that but
what was I going to say so when I posted
in game be someone posted posted saying
that there was this other one which
connecting with people on one on one
video chat and you it's it's a paid
service but people can say $0 right so
that's like I could say and I don't
quite know how it works I haven't looked
at it that much as well posted 29 I
don't know what the one of the name of
that one is but it's in the game be post
that you're posted the other one is this
app called
9k which has a lot of glues on it it
doesn't actually work what they're what
they're doing but they've salt like so
it's a mental health app it is amazing
when it's working because part of it is
you're doing courses and you find a
group to communicate about the course so
you're put into a group and how they
have the group work is they have Monday
Tuesday Wednesday Friday and if you
click on one neither says there isn't
one available or there is one available
they gives it to you in your time right
so 9:00 a.m. your time there's one
available if they're none of them work
for you then you can of course create
your own or you can just create your own
if you if you'd like to I don't because
it's not working it wouldn't actually
let me put myself in a group I have no
idea what that group looks like I don't
know like how they connect via video
chat but that system of having a problem
or something or a club right a book club
something and then being able to does
that work there's something there about
having it be just instead of you putting
in your entire schedule and having to
match you up which is hard putting in a
topic for either a one-off conversation
or an ongoing conversation and therefore
you can look at any conversation that's
going on in this business this specific
time or a topic and then you if they
don't match up for you you can create
another one within that that makes sense
and is that more simple then what I had
done on the video
I didn't quite parse that well maybe
he's saying that sorry he did a five
minute spiel and I realized I wasn't as
trying to read something else it was
amazing how the one in the in the app
worked was just that they had it wasn't
even that great because I had to click
on Monday to see if there's one on
Monday then Tuesday Tuesday but then it
would show me a time in my own time zone
and so I could join that group or I
could start my own and so having instead
of me having to put in my schedule and
then it figuring out people for me to
talk to I can start a conversation and
invite people and if people can't make
the comment can't make the time that I
have suggested they can start a new time
so anyone can either find conversations
that are happening at the time that
they're available and can either choose
to be part of any of those or start
their own or can choose the opposite of
that it's heiner table or a topic you
can either set a topic and a
conversation and start that process or
find one that's already it's already
there because all you need is a topic
ongoing or one-off and then a time I
still kind of prefer the idea of putting
in some general availability getting a
notice when two people's availabilities
when they share a topic and their
availabilities overlap and then they
could say whether they're available for
those or anytime in that overlap i've
started to build something a bit like
that in NASH she's sort of build a proof
of concept where you can have your
project you can sort of list what sort
of help you need the end goal is to sort
of try to build in like this the
solution raising is almost like an
earliest age where you can say here's
the solutions that came out of that
here's the other solutions that we know
about just like from projects right so
like here's the the solution that reason
score is doing here's the the solution
that wiki election is doing and then
here's a solution on food that no one's
tackling yet and then part of it is yeah
the projects could sort of say here's
who's involved here's the the help we
need and then members can go and see
what people need help with is that was
that of a thing to do with a scheduling
issue or is that just wool so for the
scheduling part
I kind of think in like the MVP version
we aren't it like there isn't gonna be
availability there it won't even be
smart enough for time zones you'll just
say like here's the session that we're
doing with how knack works because it's
very sort of like just a database with a
very simple and then I'm sort of
picturing like different fields that you
would pick like here's the time in
Pacific here's the time and you know UTC
here's the time in Australia like in a
certain Australian time zone just so
that like if you're use you know if you
live in North America
you're probably relatively used to
translating from PST so aureus from
Pacific time so you might be okay with
that
even though it would be ideal for you to
put it your own time
put your availability and have a
translate that to me seems sort of like
a down the road a nice to have I can
translate time zones quite well in my
head personally so I think for one I'm
hoping other people can as well so but
that would still be one are you expected
people put in their availability or are
you suggesting people put in times to
have a meeting so the first one did this
would sort the thing that I'm building
is more project-based right so it's like
we're having these meetings for this
project right so together tech might
have this meeting it might have the
project raisins wiki election won't have
the the live streams that I do on
Saturdays if you if you do anything sort
of on an a recurring basis for four
reasons core you can put that and then
people can go and see a list of either
all of the possible sessions or you know
if you're interested in reason score and
you're reading up on it and seeing what
you know what recent score needs help
with and what and maybe what content is
available you can also see hey here's
the regular sessions if you're
interested in attending those so yeah I
don't know that that solves the I mean
that's kind of narrow down the use case
because we're kind of conflating the the
team scheduling app with the with the
project raising and this is we're
raising this project and project raising
we're not this this will help with
project raising but starts initial focus
is my
understanding what my initial catalyst
for doing it right now was the pandemic
was like okay all these people are stuck
inside if we have this scheduling what a
great time for people to come on board
and be able to get to understand how
powerful video is video chat that we're
experiencing but the outside world isn't
it it's like its own project in the
project so once we have that it's a lot
easier to meet on things like hey I need
help put together tech and finding
people finding a time that works for
your team or doing but the use case is
as an individual finding people to
connect with by a video chat on topics
that are important to you and so having
it be a scheduler that that matches you
up on topics and a schedule that works
for both of you so whether that means
like I was saying and I said in the
video having individuals put in their
schedule and having the match you up or
I can put in hey I want to talk about
climate change at 3:00 p.m. on Tuesday
and if someone's like oh yeah climate
change I want to talk about that but
they're not available at 3:00 p.m. on
Tuesday because if they are let's join
me but if they aren't they can add it to
they can have a different time on that
day or at the same time different day or
you know and any of the above I think
functionally though that's the same
function except the ones for a specific
date rather than maybe repeating because
whether you put in one hour or you put
in thirty hours of availability it it's
it's still you're putting in a time span
you're saying I'd like to meet on this
topic so functionally I think those are
pretty much similar development efforts
the issue is if let's say I put in my
schedule and everyone puts in their
schedule we want to talk about climate
change then it says okay look there's
six of you who have the same schedule
the same time you can all meet at 2:00
p.m. on Thursday and then it has to send
out an invite and people have to accept
and then you create it so it's like and
because we're not Facebook it has to
email you name me like they're not going
to be checking on it so they gonna know
if you put in hey I have this one
blocked off conversation that I want to
have it's a lot easier to see like is
there zero people or a hundred people
who want anything to be part of it and
or did it generate other times right
then I can go back in and be like oh no
one signed up for mine but there are
people who are interested can I sign up
for one of theirs and possibly recombine
right like it that it sees that okay I'm
leaving this one and going to this one
am I wrong in that that's an easier app
than the one where we put in our
schedules and then it matches us up I
have to hurry adjust my thinking
I think the same like I could pretty
easily repurpose the scheduling for
projects to make the project part
optional and to even have like a topic
or something I guess my point of that
was the first version of this I don't
think you put your your availability I
think eventually you would because
that's important but in version one
where you just need to be able to to
listings and like have a list of topics
that people want to meet on and then the
proposed time and then people can sign
up for it and sort of say like yeah I'd
be interested in that I think if that's
what we're looking for I don't know that
we need an app I mean I think you could
do that in an Excel spreadsheet or a
Google sheets true yeah which personally
I think is how we should start anything
right a almost any time that we're
talking about coding something if we
don't have like a live mock-up with at
least ten users we shouldn't code
anything well there are some things that
that that that you can't bootstrap that
way like if if you wanted it to choose
for people I guess you could write some
code on them to have a search but having
an availability and having a find
availability isn't something I would do
in Google sheets but if you're just
moving into certain times of the product
right that's that's one thing that I
think that is in the coded version the
spreadsheet doesn't have all the
features the spreadsheet just starts
to collect the people love them saying
that there are some minimum viable
products that you cannot do in a goggle
sheet that's alright okay okay but
because some of the other stuff we were
throwing around I can't imagine how
you'd do that first to negotiate but if
you're just putting in dates and times
and topics then we might be able to find
a way to organize that I'm trying to
think of how it would be organized
though because it could just be you know
a list of topics and then people could
search and then put in their times yeah
there's stuff in the comments sort of
saying like why do you need scheduling I
think once we have a lot of people
theoretically yet you don't you need
scheduling if there's a thousand people
on the site all looking at different
topics odds are you're gonna have you
know five to ten people interested
making just jump into a room but when
you're starting with like ten or twenty
people in order to actually gain
traction and start to have meetings
especially if we're across time zones I
think you'd still need scheduling
someone needs to write like this meeting
is happening because we scheduled it so
the people who are hosting it were able
to schedule around it no one to join and
I think you would need to do that at
least at the start to get people sort of
on board to say okay can we all meet at
this time regularly great let's keep
meeting then and then once that has
dealt enough of an audience
theoretically you can start meeting
without a schedule sort of like how you
know people may have some people might
be watching this or maybe watching
certain live streams just because it's
on Facebook and because they saw they're
like oh neat
but that's cos Facebook has so many
people it has that as an option yeah and
we we already have an open game be zoom
room right and people use that for a
while but from after a while you know
there's there's no there's no reason to
go there because no one would be there
and it's hard to sit on it with it open
on your computer all the time so I think
without scheduling you're still gonna
have a very very low you know even with
tens of thousands of people I don't I
don't know that I would still go there
and say okay I want to talk now but I'd
rather do you know something coming
through like so what we tried to do in
game B in the very beginning right but
the
and then you'd go in and no one would be
there but when someone was there it was
really awesome and it was really cool
for like a week or two having a
scheduling app that just concentrates on
that so the idea is having a zoom room
that's paid for having multiple zoom
rooms and then having people vote on
what topic is most relevant or you know
like which rooms talking about which
which sorry 15 things coming through
ones having a calendar for each room
where someone can say hey this is the
topic that we're talking about at this
time so come and join and if you can't
then you might want to have that same
conversation somewhere else right like
at a different time but oh and then if
there's two happening simultaneously
that's when you want a second zoom
account or there's two conversations
happy yeah two conversations having
simultaneous they're more than 100
people kazuma can can coordinate a
hundred people
than also potentially reaching out to
other communities that could really use
connection in the in the pandemic to say
hey this space is for parents right to
come and talk about parenting during
this time once your kids are in bed cuz
time is all around the world right at
any different any given time
I didn't or yeah having limits to groups
so I know you're afraid to think oh yeah
I don't know I so he mentioned earlier
that five to ten people group so yeah we
are hoping to limit each group to four
right Julie or I mean that number may
vary but our initial plan is like you
know I would really like numbers so
limited to four like even the Omega
Group this the one that Eric's trying to
grow there were like seven people that
are this week and it doesn't work for me
I need to have four people having a
conversation maximum not all the people
said half the people aren't talking and
they're just watching they're not
getting their voice heard I don't feel
heard because I feel like I can't
monopolize even a quarter of the time
and I want to be able to feel like I
could invoke once a quarter of the time
like it just for me it doesn't but I
don't but at the same time you don't
want to split like six is kind of the
splitting point right so you if you have
five people okay
if you know six people you split into
groups of three and zoom can do that so
doing a very beta scheduling app where
people can log in because the whole
point also is if we're doing it just
with in-game B I feel like we would have
gained traction already with the amount
of things and I put out there that are
very like this right like crickets
so like this isn't going to be an
internal game B thing it's something
that is like for Humanity while we're
stuck inside during a pandemic to
connect them on topics of interest and
so having it be a very beta youth login
so you're not showing up naked and being
a troll maybe there's a nudity one I
don't know enough people who want
clothing optional options great but like
you know that it we're not having the
same problems a lot of the stuff you
have an actual account that you're
logging into and then then it it helps
you schedule the conversations right
which zoom room am I in as there's a
problem with one
can we you know buy a new one and add it
in can someone donate one for six hours
per day like all the different um pieces
but it also didn't get traction there's
no one besides this person who was like
yes I can I can create this so maybe I
will contact Sam and who is the person
from there oh I see ADA went to go get
her a package she said and so like I
just think this is like an a time where
society can bear you get much more
divided as we already are with toilet
paper being short and people blaming
everyone else like like I'm healthy so I
can get it and like just societies in
the process of going crazy and so to be
able to offer it some kind of glimmer of
hope that's available to everyone that's
not about not about game B but very game
B I think if you can connect over video
and then it like if it's simple enough
that anyone can add a zoom right that
when you have a community when you have
something that we're not discussing we
can have the ones that are more um
what's the word like concrete likes
people want to discuss climate change we
want to discuss parenting people wanted
to discuss sporting events I don't know
having four or five or and then as they
don't register at that you want to know
and wants to use them having having them
rotating what that topic is right well
the sports people really do like talking
and they show up constantly but I don't
know exactly what that would look like
if we're using it to facilitate a zoom
room a cafe but so we can just know
what's happening in which you remote
what time and as an individual I can
suggest something or and or join so a to
pass one to put in your availability one
to just put in a date a time and for
availability I'm thinking it might be
easiest this may or may not work is just
to say you know for these days of the
week for these hours I tend to be
available so that make a rather simpler
interface rather than having all the
options repeat
monthly days and stuff like that because
most people have some sort of regular
weekly schedule but not everyone but
you're right then we still need a
notification system the other option is
yeah just some place that to list that
you have times and you have dates and
times and topics and then people can
search and and express interest in that
date and time and topic yes - what
Enrico said yes the idea is anyone can
start a group but whatever the beta
version is is gonna limit that we only
have four rooms if we only have light we
need to choose ones that are more that
of a higher threshold of people who are
interested yeah although I I mean if
we're I mean I still don't think like
the the feature and zoom of taking a
large group of people and splitting it
up into smaller things it's gonna be
much of a thing the problem is people
don't know when to be together so I
guess that does become a problem if you
get a lot of people but I think the
bigger issue is finding the time to be
together rather than splitting up a
large group so I mean even if yeah I
coordinate that but sorry what do you
mean by finding the time to be together
you mean like the scheduling part of it
like finding a time that for people I
don't I don't know how often you're
gonna really have four people more than
four people who found a time and in just
any one of them you know someone just
chooses to create a free zoom account
and start a room with four people you
have 45 minutes on the free version or
you know if you're using a spreadsheet
then the top four people do a meeting
and the fifth person you know goes gets
a free zoom accountant puts in a zoom
link into the spreadsheet right
it's just handled by convention is there
a way to do this on spreadsheet and
Facebook group
so that anyone can theoretically join
the Facebook group to get access to the
spreadsheet and can possibly post like
we don't want everyone posting I might
have a conversation this time in this
day that's not sure we totally do in the
beginning but once we have a hundred
people we don't want a hundred people
posting what they want to have a
conversation about and it's not going to
connect them but having a spreadsheet
that is topic dating time and you're
gonna have to feel like it'll be always
in Pacific Standard Time or always in
GMT time which one you can make the most
sense they stopping it in the GMT time
and then you get to switch it for you
so having the time and then you sign up
for that and then you put the link in
but you want to know people are gonna
show up that's part of the problem is
like I put out things that are hey let's
talk about this at this time and then
one person might want to I'm not looking
to have a one-on-one conversation I'm
looking to have like it's which to make
this work I would have a one-on-one
conversation no problem but the constant
you're the only one who shows up and
nobody else shows up and it's or
constantly just being two of you when
you're wanting to have a group
conversation he's a problem but is the
I'm in rambling on is there a way to do
this with a spreadsheet and they so I
think you could create a spreadsheet the
first column would be topic second
column would be dating time and in GMT
or a Zulu time and and then you know
that third fourth and fifth and six
columns would be someone marking that
they have an interest right tabs would
be for date that seems weird or topic
having four different topics and having
it be I don't I don't see a reason and
breaking it down into tabs just having
like one tab for topics and then one tab
for people who want to sign up and then
you can start to get like account for
purpose of the could sign up for the
same top important ones you could have a
hundred people sign up for the same
topic if you want
so that's more than but how are they
getting and finding when they're
available the point is to have a topic
and the time there is no way to kind of
say I'm sorry I can't make this time in
this topic but I could make any of these
times you can put out a second one right
I can't make that but I could make this
time and put out a second one but you
can't really put out a like I'm not
coordinating people to get together and
have no conversation I have enough
enough going on it's hard enough to
coordinate me having those conversations
around my schedule but so the
spreadsheet because what what we would
want from the spreadsheet is the
communication that something has
happened in this topic this time and
then how many people are interested in
that how many people are actually gonna
show up and be part of it and then yeah
because like Facebook becomes
unmanageable very fast like a hundred
people having regular conversations is
almost too much for a spreadsheet to
handle but that's a good problem to have
right when it gets too big for for that
but I just like I want to be able to
offer the world this option even if this
option is start your own Facebook group
around a topic and figure out a zoom
room write about something that's that's
important to you that this is an option
and then creating the parallel platform
that helps everyone come on to that
platform so that everyone can access
this and maybe Facebook takes it on no
something like that which I don't want
but there's a post about a question
about donation pools and know there's in
the game be group someone's working on
making a generic kind of game be
crowdfunding platform but we could also
you know if we wanted to write out a
specification and do a quick video we
could do a gosh what's the crowdfunding
site that they don't really care what
you're doing
yeah GoFundMe you you know we could
throw up a GoFundMe yeah we just have
all of our
for together tech we have all of our
regular issues which is like we don't
have a bank account
oops going on like we need to figure out
that piece of it and that is part of
yeah that's part of it together tech
needs to figure out but we're not really
there yet because we don't have people
who are looking to fund us but maybe we
do yeah so if we want to just give it a
try I think a goo sheet with topic
column date and time column and then
zoom link column and then for slots for
people to to indicate that they're
interested and I would put my name in
there or I would just say yes yeah
however we'd have to see what convinced
works I probably first name would would
do this once we get past four we're good
because if we have five then we don't
split into groups if we have six we
split into groups of three if we don't
like yeah why we hang up to a hundred I
mean that won't be a problem I would
delete the columns to the right and say
you know once it fills up to four people
you just stop and the call has and you
just say if there's not four people
you're not gonna have a call or you
could say three to four or something
like that and bring out the fourth
column or you can go to five or whatever
but a good option part of the issue
though with anyone can post on it can
say yes there's the zoom link here's the
topic here's the time and I'm a new
person coming on or emini coming on
after people have posted how do I find
like they're not in an order that's
helping me is there a way to export a
spreadsheet to a calendar my guess is no
or whatever ago you would sort you would
sort by the the columns and the order so
it's sort by topic so first you'd go
look you'd control F to find the topic
if you kind of know what the wording is
or you could browse and then you look at
you know and then didn't it everything
under that topic would be listed I can't
imagine there'd be more than you know a
page worth of events on any topic and
then when you're done or the date passes
you would delete that row
and it's also like everything chicken
and eggs like if we don't have enough
people to try it out then it's not
viable like the three of us know when
we're having the conversation we don't
need it for the three of us need it for
like humanity but we don't need it for
Humanity because we can't do it for
Humanity so like a hundred people who
are lonely and want to have a
conversation trained and I don't even
know how to do that that marketing piece
is broken for every one of the ideas I
have like getting people to the thing
seems to be very very not my talent I
think you guys mentioned it earlier but
the idea of having a Facebook group
where just somebody posts and says I
want to talk about this topic and then
that post becomes the conversation
around ok who's interested in what times
do we want and blah blah blah and use
that you know until you get like 10 20
people and then you can start to figure
out ok now with these 10 20 people how
do we do a spreadsheet right and 10 20
month might be too low if there's a
bunch of topics but if there's like two
that seem to resonate especially strong
that might be fine there's ten topics
you probably won't like a hundred
because you want like a decent size in
each group and then and then you can
start at that point probably build up
the spreadsheet when you figure out how
people are using it how the
conversations go where they're trying to
arrange their time and how often people
tend to you know oh look at this time
spot has 20 people so I had its foot
into groups
this time spot there's been two of them
they've been trying to meet for four
weeks what can we do to help those two
cases so is the idea here to have not a
one-off conversation but a weekly
conversation or a bi-weekly conversation
I think your original topic was a
one-off conversation right but it was
both it was I mean the truth is is it's
it's easier for people to jump on board
to a one-off conversation there don't
feel like they're committing to anything
at the same time tool to create
community within the pandemic multiple
conversations over a course of time is
going to be much more valuable to people
but again do they know that poor thing
are they coming on boards the idea is
both that you do have in fact I like
weakly better or bi-weekly like how
often are you meeting and what's the
first one and then you know how many are
there and are you still open right
because if you have enough people like
you have 12 people and we break into
groups of four every
but we don't want more people right are
you open to get if you're not open to
have any people then that's what you
delete it off of there well I mean once
you have the first meeting you could say
repeating I think you should take it off
the spreadsheet because you don't need
any more people but you might be like
there might be especially if you're have
a paid some account you might be willing
to have up to 100 people but that's not
going to create the intimate community
so I like the idea like at the Omega on
Tuesday getting 1215 people and then
breaking off into groups so I know I'm
talking to the same community of people
but not the same people all the time if
that make sense so I'm not talking to
the same three or four people but I'm
talking to the same 50 people yeah but
yeah I just I just think that you're
already having trouble of not having
enough people in general and then you're
now you're limiting it down to one hour
a week and trying to get more people I
think it'd be better if the system it if
it wasn't you know breaking people up
after they get to the same point of time
but breaking people up on all the
different potential times that they have
is it worth it to make this only a
solution raising type cafe so it's not
gonna solve all of the problems for
Humanity but there isn't a single person
that I know of who doesn't care about
something so having it be a actual
project-based conversation where the
first one is that solution right like
maybe they're in some you know you're
you're talking with people on education
and forming a group around that and then
continuing on having that conversation
until you feel you've done all you can
do I'm completely pivoting and changing
the entire point all right yeah stronger
because if if you can say like here's
the time here's the topic and people can
vote on the topic I think it's easier to
say yes to something that's more
concrete that you're like here's the
time here's this do on in or not and
like here's the topics that we're
talking about which one do you like as
opposed to like who wants to talk about
stuff that becomes a much more nebulous
conversation where people might just get
lost in the mire trying to think about
ideas to possibly talk about and like
we've seen that that does kind of work
with all the meetings that you know
we're
all part of they have varying success
rates but we do it you know we do them
we get people joining in on some of them
we get feedback we get some Facebook
viewers and and YouTube ones you just in
my experience if you can be specific
that appeals to people more like yeah
like there's something about this
solution raises and yes we're important
the infancy we're still figuring out
what those look like but they're
powerful like being able to be part of a
conversation that can generate solutions
is exactly what the world needs right
now and then it becomes like wait why
are we generating solutions for the
platform itself right like so we can
make this easier is that we can do its
own thing and so having one Facebook
group that is solution raising that is
like hey when well and then having
various topics taking for the top four
topics that people maybe want to talk
about and in coordinating coordinating
that or yeah no because I'm not having a
Facebook group for each individual I
never mind she's like or we know it's
not up to him and he don't care do care
about multiple ones right like I'm like
I care about it occasion and food what
happened family did he drop himself down
yeah I think so thank you said I'll be
back or something okay I guess just
raise your hand family when you're ready
raise your hands
see that kid stop dropping out who knows
who knows the world topics zombie 1
Facebook group and then having is there
is there a game be conversations group
yes okay so it seems like that's the
spot for this to live to start with at
least just to like find the people and
to post the things I'm like hey who
wants to meet on X no because
conversation strangely isn't that it is
only for posting your conversations
you've already had it's not for actually
finding people to have conversations
with well alright so if you see
someone's conversation and you post
underneath like oh I want to have a
conversation with you that's totally
cool but they don't want it to turn into
what we would make it
okay okay plus I don't want it to be
game B people as much as I love game B
people right conversations on stop I
want to be able to say listen world we
could come up with actual solutions you
are empowered have a conversation that
is about empowering humanity like well
you're stuck inside with the coronavirus
that we don't maybe have any control
over you we all of the the cracks that
this has shown in society look at what
we can do from that right and greediness
like let's talk about food let's talk
about energy let's talk about education
let's talk about and then coordinating
that I like that idea way more at least
to start with then open conversations
and I think one leads to to the other
right because right people away or 500
people who were like hey wait who's
interested in this topic well cool let's
start a conversation on that yeah and
and so it's like topic and then you can
also so you like the education there
could be like its own spreadsheet on
education and then people can be like
yeah I want to talk about my favorite
teacher right like it doesn't need to be
something that's like problem from point
A to point B if people want to have that
conversation right what major of teacher
your favorite what was your favorite
class because those are me I love having
those conversations but creating the
umbrella under which you're having those
conversations and finding the people to
have the lesson how about a game be
Facebook group asks and offers help seat
conversations like asking for a
conversation and offering asking and
operated started Bentley put up his hand
he's back
I'm gonna guess he put up his hand sorry
did I preemptively put you in definitely
just fixing my audio got ready to prep
your hand and I thought you had I'm sure
you would have again you never knew I
could have waited we need to as people
say the concept of game be put in
simpler terms something that's leave it
off was the same person's before us the
problem it's really weird because
Enrico's shows up but the other people
don't
it's was it like the same person one of
them was Sam cuz I went to go see but I
don't I don't I don't know but so a
Facebook group that is solution raising
raising solutions in this area the issue
is no solution ratios but at the same
time once you've seen one it's pretty
self-evident and the understanding this
isn't set in concrete
we're working out how to do solution
raising to like what works so much other
I'm holding I don't know if you guys saw
him holding one later today on
pandemics basically on infectious
disease it's like let's try let's see if
we can fail this is a hard one to talk
about people's emotions are heightened
I have no solution for it really besides
all of the solutions I have so far like
health care solutions and such but not
one for and and it also like with 10,000
people than $1,000 I don't know what
could you do with that no idea what
we're gonna see so there's that today
than you guys are doing the one tomorrow
on community as I'm flying out to
Alberta um actually not available for
tomorrow's either yeah I think it's
gonna end up being kind of a new crew I
think is gonna be me I think Edward and
we'll see who else joins us on one one
of the last ones and it's me Kylie Eric
and Mark Fraser on the the one today so
that should be should be good and then
no one else they wouldn't even I find it
so frustrating when I think is there
like like when you need to get posts
approved you no one will approve it I
don't I'm like this is exactly in this
space I wanted to suggest it like this
coronavirus Vegas is like cool let's
have an open conversation let's actually
come up with solutions and no they want
to I don't understand why people like
this isn't the same I'm not requiring
money from people there's no nothing
about trying to sort of start this with
a more specific ask like these these
solution raising
trying it to not be game B do we just
want to rename the game B projects two
together tech it's that kind of like
because that's sort of what the game B
project space is and solution raising is
sort of the first part of the together
tech you know solution to project
actually working on the project funnel
there's like both wait because one we
are attached to game be like we're on
the we couldn't possibly were on the
page but of like we're the only ones
really participating there's a handful
of other people are participating the
idea is that people in game behalf
project so why are we not coming
together and creating on UN solutions
there's also people outside of game
you've never even heard of game B you
have projects that I have been inviting
but I'm suggesting come and be part of
game B projects but I like the idea of
being game be projects because we're not
big enough to stand on our own it the
only reason I don't is just because if
we're trying to get other people
involved as soon as you see game B
projects that starts the squirrel
conversation of what's game B and then
you you know you kind of you might lose
people as far as they get distracted and
go and do other stuff but if it's it's
own thing of a standalone and you have
to be called together tech but if it's
something that doesn't reference
anything else and we're saying hey come
and be a part of this their solution
rating and projects and we're doing all
the stuff that idea is standalone and
the page is standalone I like both ideas
because I think that it might be worth
asking the game be people like do you
have to have game be in the name for it
to be on the page okay that's why Cuba
2.0 named it till I can't beat Cuba 2.0
having projects come together and create
Omni win solutions is already very game
B we're like yes I get B we need to run
the people need to understand game B
before they come on for but at the same
time I don't want someone coming on
board and not understanding not game B
but like why baby right well I we've
talked about the thing with together
tech is like we all sort of have our
ideas and we seem to be you know in sort
of unison on it's Omni when and the
various different pieces so we just
explained knows cuz I mean I've seen so
many converse
Shinzon the game bSpace that go you know
that goes super deep and people talking
about it and novels are written about
like what is game B people won't read
that much if we're just trying to be
like hey do you want to come to a
session to talk about this there should
probably be some kind of an intro like
hey we Romney win and it's this and it's
not for profit or whatever phrases we
choose to use to describe that group we
can sort of choose which elements of
game B we think we should focus on and
just do that but again that is if we
have to keep game B in the name right
now that does seem like kind of the best
spot to get people interested because
that is the most alignment and so it's
no yeah I think we'd look into changing
it once it becomes an issue I don't
think there's a problem either way I
think right now we can just invite
people to projects whether they're game
B or not if they have a project and or
they want to find a project and then if
from there they find they game be space
great or people from game B find it
which is much more of the arrow that it
goes towards and I don't think again
which is why I don't think we're big
enough to stand on our look on our own
is people know game B they don't know
together tech and having a meta project
of people being able to come together
just like game B's the best branding for
it at the moment and once there's enough
of us coordinating and it's like this is
the meta project that is together tech
then um then it involves its own right
if the three of us are deciding it's it
was not yeah matter project it's yeah I
guess we might get was like if we keep
the name have some kind of an intro on
the page you know that's sort of like
here's what we stand for you know here's
what game B means to this like to this
page to this group you know if you want
to go and squirrel and figure out what
gimme means everyone have fun but in
context of this group here's the
operating principles we're open to
change
let's go yeah like we are just coming
together for you know I'm new in
solutions for our projects and creating
the infrastructure that helps facilitate
that together and dealing with the
emotional fallout of all of that fun fun
things which aren't actually fun things
but I don't think that either game B
projects or together tech face
group is the Facebook group that is the
solution raising people want to join to
be part of a conversation on solutions
like having that's for like solution
raising specifically like come here if
you want to talk with other people on
video chat about solutions right well I
think so I think I've heard sort of two
different parts there's just the
conversation part like going and
chatting about topics and that I don't
think has anything to do with together
tech your game you projects or that and
then there's the like trying to have a
conversation around a solution that if
it goes well should eventually turn into
a project to me that's like almost like
using you know game a terms that's like
building the funnel for the projects
that's saying yeah here's a list of
things and also sort of like the the
fact that we linked it to game B
projects or to gather tech they seem
very sort of you know there's a lot of
energy there there's a lot of like it's
trying to do the same thing it helps
build the like okay they're trying to do
sort of end to end start with the what
are you trying to solve and then going
into the projects and so on
so I think the the separation is if it's
something like the solution everything
as we've done so far that does seem game
B projects if we're talking about like
an open conversation around whatever
yeah that's not that can but I also
don't do don't think that sounds
something like a solution that's just a
conversation I think also though like if
it's tied to the Facebook group on
projects we already don't have that many
people without projects who are there
and that's the point is like anyone can
be part of this and so it is the funnel
it could be the funnel but I think
designing it in the place it's the
funnel possibly to isn't because it's
like you have the conversation there's
no kind of stress on you have to come up
with a solution you're gonna work on
this is like a place to play and say hey
look what we could come up with in and
out or imagine if we were able to create
working groups and hey we could also do
that like we can actually have if
something was generated within a
conversation and you want to actually
have it be actionable how do we create
in the world how do we get 10,000 people
hundred dollars once you've had you know
a bunch of these and that same question
has come up and then it becomes a
project under the projects right
either the individual project or the
project of how do we facilitate these
conversations and facilitate a project
that is created from them from the
ground up through conversation I just
talked myself into creating yet another
Facebook group I already created one
this week on Kyle sees where it's
hilarious cuz everyone it's a different
version don't let that then they work
for him I'm like we're just trying to
figure out coaching without a central
leader if you don't want the like this
is not high school I just can't do the
drama not doing the drama posed to be a
men to go back to the question before
you in a Lagasse you're thinking about
starting a new group that we can call
whatever that we move solution raising
to and then the idea is if somebody
wants to start a solution you say great
by the way if you're interested head
over there like head over to projects if
you want help and if you want this sort
of environment but then there's a page
for sort of both types of conversations
just to like casually discussing stuff
and then actually sort of conversation
with the purpose of hopefully get a
solution I sorry I don't really
understand but a Facebook group that is
facilitating that anyone can be part of
a conversation not when we are doing
solution raising its particular together
tech is doing them we're following that
format we're trying to figure out that
format and probably at least one of us
is participating and it's recorded and
put on our YouTube channel the idea of a
Facebook group is that it's not
broadcast anyone can participate will be
a zoom call we're coordinating that but
also if you want to record and pick and
post here right what these solutions are
and how do we how do we do coordinate
that right maybe there's one posting for
food and one for this and keep posting
videos under that yeah okay a separate
Facebook group for the like non and
solution emphasis type conversations no
solution raising is still the those are
the conversations are facilitating
they're just not solution raisings of
together tech is doing
like it's like the true crowd-sourced
hey do you have a topic you wanted to
have a solution on how do we help you
coordinate a group to do that and then
even if we're not there how do we
facilitate that and how do we have
hundreds of people hopefully participate
in it so that everyone feels empowered
to create solutions together to actually
talk on video chat and have the same
validation
once the conversations are still in the
context of trying to find a solution to
something and beyond like the idea is to
pick topics that are problematic in
society that needs solutions and
facilitate conversations under the
umbrella of that problem that we're
coming up with solutions for so one of
the easiest points to get into is to try
a solution raising yourself right tried
to come up with solutions within it many
of them aren't going to work many of
them are gonna have possibly like I
think any group on part of em is gonna
have a solution we're probably all like
that but there might be four people who
get together who are waiting for someone
else to help with all the solutions I
don't know and that's part of trying is
facilitating conversations empowering
people and giving them a project because
that is how you create community and
help people have personal growth is like
you figure out your that some
people don't know how to figure out
their doing it in a group setting
when you have a project work through is
like ideal there's so many reasons you
feel that was not the vision of the game
to this hour it was just conversations
any conversation I don't care if it's on
sports or your show last night but we
don't have a lot of ways that's harder -
harder to coordinate so having a
Facebook group so we do have a Facebook
group but then it'd be like comment
video chats about everything and it all
it everything under the Sun it's a
medium to you is too much whereas people
feeling the stress that I've been
feeling for decades of like our world is
falling apart this is like touching
every different area uh-huh having
people from that space be able to be
empowered find their group of people and
connect or video chat and come up with
actual solutions is to me what shifted
during this hour and now that's what I
want to get in on stir the rest of
humanity where the problem solvers and
how do we connect them
I love those have you met conversations
whoever said this yes that would be
awesome however also we're not there yet
I think that is part of like having
people conversations are we are we gonna
record them are they gonna be posted as
a very one-off thing saying with is
there an artist here who can draw
something up eventually having that be
part of the process or if you have a
single solution raising like we're doing
food and then you have every individual
group creating a solution then working
through a process to actually showcase
that solution like we've yet to come up
with an actual solution during
solutionizing we come up with dozens of
solutions right that are like not really
looked into think about how long the
conversation for just the schedule a
like it could do this and it could do
that being able to actually say yes this
is enough of a kernel to want to give it
back to want to report it to the group
right to say hey who wants to work on
this and then other people can generate
conversations from that conversation or
start again at zero right and yes then
it will come up naturally I'm hoping of
like how do we take notes of these
conversations how do we actually pass
this information back to the group but
the bigger deal is that people get
together and realize that in groups of
four they can come up with a solution so
why aren't we doing this on a massive
scale like honestly once we have a
platform on humanity where you can log
in and have a conversation that has a
real impact to be able to create tasks
like anyone can do and follow through on
those tasks and hire people to do the
other parts this all happens so very
fast but getting to that point when we
have zero people and zero with four
people but like not enough people to do
the work not enough money to pay people
who would be willing to do the work it's
a much slower process or figuring how to
do it on the current on current tech and
I think we're doing a pretty good job
Facebook in a spreadsheet you know the
other group is going off can be so much
less drama and people who need coaching
turns out who would have thought oh all
right I have my solution raising in an
hour and my brain needs a break so does
anyone have us have anything else they
would like to add to the conversation or
should we and here nope that's good
ending point all right so I'm gonna
create a Facebook group and once people
are in the Facebook group we'll figure
out how to make a spreadsheet to
facilitate the process all right I
Facebook by YouTube